McCulloch, Frank Papers 5883
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Frank McCulloch Papers
1940-1985
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
McCulloch, Frank
5883
25 cubic feet
25 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
General correspondence. Alphabetically organized by author's surname, institution, or organization, then chronologically.
5725201
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, January 14, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 17, 2019
Scope and Contents
Includes material directed to Frank McCulloch as well as responses from McCulloch or members of his staff at the National Labor Relations Board. March 1961-August 1970. Personal correspondence - Chronologically organized, then alphabetically by author's surname, institution or organization. Much of the correspondence overlaps with the materials included in General correspondence. March 1961-Dec. 1963 and Jan. 1968-Aug. 1970.
Cross-filed copies of Frank W. McCulloch's letters. Organized alphabetically by author's surname, institution, or organization, then chronologically. Material spans from Feb. 1961 to July 1964. Much of the material is also found in General correspondence or Personal correspondence. Subject files: from the 1950s through the late 1980s (bulk 1961-1970) Speeches and testimonies - supporting publications - teaching materials - administrative and personnel files - photographs and audio tapes.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4057: James A. Gross NLRB Files /4057 AV: James A. Gross NLRB Audiocassettes /4117 P: ILR School Photographs /4117 P: ILR School Photographs /4166: James A. Gross Additional NLRB Research Files 5204 mf: Southern Tenant Farmers Union Records on Microfilm 5225: ALES Records 5541: Philip Taft Papers 5583/1: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 1 5740 OH: NLRB 50th Anniversary Conference Tapes and Transcripts 5745 P: ACWA Publicity Department Photographs 5775: NAA Records 5780/083: ILGWU Sol Chaikin Papers 5780/103: ILGWU Political Department Records 5843 OHM: NLRB Oral History Project II Master Tapes 5843 OHT: NLRB Oral History Project II Transcripts 5914: Douglas H. Soutar Papers 6021/008: Theodore W. Kheel Books and Articles 6379: Sam Zagoria National Labor Relations Board Papers 6391: William B. Gould IV NLRB Papers
Arrangement
Series I. CORRESPONDENCE
Sub-Series A: General Correspondence Sub-Series B: Personal Correspondence Sub-Series C: Cross-filed copies of Frank W. McCulloch's Letters
Series II. SUBJECT FILES
Series III: SPEECHES AND TESTIMONIES
Sub-Series A: Speeches By Frank McCulloch Sub-Series B: Speeches by NLRB Officials
Series IV: SUPPORTING PUBLICATIONS
Series V: TEACHING MATERIALS
Series VI: ADMINISTRATIVE AND PERSONNEL FILES
Series VII: PHOTOGRAPHS AND AUDIO TAPES
McCulloch, Frank W., 1905-1996.; United States. National Labor Relations Board
5725201
- Series SERIES I. CORRESPONDENCE
  - Sub-Series A: General Correspondence
    - A (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Scope and Contents
      Includes material from Douglas Anderson of the Honorable Paul Douglas's office re: time lag in cases; Dr. Leslie Aspin re: expanding the study on remedies and reinstatement
    - B, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Includes material from Solomon Barkin - "The Resolution of Industrial Conflict." (no location given) 16 April 1969; and Derek Bok
    - C (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - D (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Includes Material from John Dunlop
    - E (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - F, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Includes material from the Honorable Charles Fahy such as a copy of "Notes for Remarks on Administering the Oath to Mr. Ordman," July 5, 1967
    - G (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - H, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Includes material from the Honorable Robert Hampton, Chairman of the Civil Service Commission; Paul Herzog - a humorous 'mock decision' written in 1949 and circulated among the NLRB; Senator Lister Hill; and Vice President Hubert Humphrey.
    - I-J (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Includes material from Jefferson Standard Broadcasting Company - a copy of an editorial criticizing the pro-labor bent of the NLRB; Joseph Jenkins - former Board member; President Lyndon Johnson.'
    - K, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Includes material from Eugene keeney of the Chamber of Commerce of the United States - enclosed a speech by Fred Borch, General Electric Company. "Tomorrows Customers." The Sales Executive Club of New York. 15 September 1964; President John Kennedy; Attorney General Robert Kennedy; Jay Kramer, Chairman of the New York State Labor Relations Board.
    - L, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Includes material from Morris Leibman - "American Bar Association Standing Committee on Education about Communism and its Contrast with Liberty Under Law." February 1967; Bert Liss; Bert Luskin "Presidential Address." National Academy of Arbitrators. Cleveland. 1 February 1968
    - Mc (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Includes materials from Frank McCallister, Director of the Labor education Division at Roosevelt University; Arthur McDowell -- enclosed documents from the Council Against Communist Aggression
    - Mc (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Includes materials from the Honorable John Macy, Chairman of the US Civil Service Commission, Rose Madden, Regional Director of the Region 13 of the NLRB, re: Checker Taxi Company, Inc.; George Meany
    - N-O (Box 1, Folder 14)
      Includes material from the National Institute of Labor Education (NILE); Francis O'Connell, Olin Corporation, re: commending the Board on a more employer-favorable decision
    - P (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Includes material from the Pacific Maritime Association; Honorable Ian Percival of the House of Commons; Honorable Roman Pucinski; LaRoy Purdy, Director of the Civic Affairs Department of the Communication Workers of America (CWA), re: CWA Opinion Research Projects and Confidential Report to CWA Executive Board.
    - R, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      Includes material from Joseph Rauh, United Auto Workers, re: Kohler contempt case, free speech issues; Roosevelt University Commencement Address (see also Speeches and Publications - Series IV); Alfred Rota, Secretary and Business Representative of the Upholsterers' International Union, re: proposals to the Board concerning changing policy in cases of tie votes, also response written to Lefkoe, M.R. "Double Standard - Critics See NLRB Bias against Management Free Speech." Wall Street Journal 19 July 1963.
    - S-Se (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Includes material from Arthur Schlesinger
    - Sh-St (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Su, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      includes material from James Sundquist of the Brookings Institution--draft (1967) of Chapter 6 (name of publications not given) titled "For Minorities, Equal Rights;" and from the Supreme Court
    - T-V, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      Includes material from the Textile Workers Union of America - resolution entitled "Denial of Constitutional Rights to Trade Unionists in the South," November 14, 1961; and from the Honorable Frank Thompson, Jr., re: unsolicited letter in support of McCulloch for reappointment to Chairman of the NLRB
    - W (Box 1, Folder 21)
      Includes materials from Labor Secretary Willard Wirtz and Edward Wynne, Textile Workers Union of America, re: memo concerning an NLRB leaflet on the right to organize
    - Y (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Z (Box 1, Folder 23)
      Includes materials from Albert Zack, Director of AFL-CIO Department of Public Relations, re: NLRB decisions under the Kennedy Administrative; Sam Zagoria; Peter Zenkl
  - Sub-Series B: Personal Correspondence
    - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      August 1970 - January 1970
    - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      December 1969-January 1969, note - includes a letter to President Nixon requesting reconsideration of the reduction in the Fiscal Year 1971 Budget Request; also includes a draft of a reply for the President to a letter from Mr. James McCabe of Kinkead Industries Inc.
    - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      December 1968-January 1968
    - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      December 1963-January 1963, *note, there are no files between December 1963 and January 1968
    - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      December 1962-January 1962, note - includes a letter to Vice President Lyndon Johnson, re: providing notes for the VP's April 6 address to labor reporters and editors
    - Correspondence, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      December 1961-March 1961
  - Sub-Series C: Cross-filed copies of Frank W. McCulloch's Letters
    - A-B (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - C (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - D-E (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - F-G (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - H-K (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - L-M (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - N-R (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - S (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - T-Z (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Series SERIES II. SUBJECT FILES
  - Access to Employees, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
    Includes: handwritten notes, Bok, Derek "The Regulation of Campaign Tactics in Representation Elections Under the National Labor Relations Act." Harvard Law Review. 78:38(1964); 38-141
  - Administration of Labor Law - Law Reviews., 1962-1971 (Box 3, Folder 3-6)
    Includes: testimonies of Roger C. Cramton, Chairman of Administrative Conference of the US. 1971. H.R. 7152 To Amend the Labor-Management Relations Act. Testimony before the Special Subcommittee on Labor, Washington, D.C. May. And 1971. H.R. 14-15-16 and H.R. 3809 Bills to Establish a Consumer Protection Agency and an Office of Consumer Affairs. Testimony before the Subcommittee on Legislation and Military Operations, Washington, D.C. May., various journal articles, 1962-1971
  - Administrative Problems, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Includes: statement of Frank McCulloch (1966) and Congressional Record.
  - Allied Supermarkets Case (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Includes: letters to and from the National Association of Manufacturers (NAM), Senator Yarborough; news articles; Congressional Record - discussion of the case in testimonies before the Ervin Subcommittee.
  - Appointment of Annuitant Hearing Examiners, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Includes: handwritten notes and drafts of "The Legality of the Appointment of Annuitant Hearing Examiners Under Section 11 of the Administrative Procedures Act, 1967"
  - Appointments to the NLRB late '70s, early '80s. Re: John Van de Water, Betty Murphy, William Lubbers (Box 3, Folder 10-12)
    includes: testimonies of hearings on nominations, hand written notes, Chamber of Commerce statement of position, correspondence among National Labor Relations Board (NLRB) members, news clippings
  - Arbitration (Box 3, Folder 13-31)
    Includes: handwritten notes, cases, published pamphlets, speeches, papers, reports, correspondence, documents from NLRB meetings with the National Academy of Arbitrators
  - Authorization Cards (Box 4, Folder 1-11)
    Includes: Cases and analyses/reports on various cases, statistics on cases, memos, NAM position speeches, statement by Secretary of Labor Wirtz, speech by McCulloch on labor law
  - Bornstein Case Study of Labor Relations, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    "The Calvin Coolidge Chair Co. A Study of Labor Relations Conflict and Cooperation in a Single Firm." Unpublished Report, Amherst: University of Massachusetts
  - Brickman, Harry - Operations Analysis, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 13-27)
    Includes: Monthly Labor Review 1966, NLRB Statistical Reports, recommendations for improvement
  - Bureau of the Budget - NLRB Long Range Plans (Box 4, Folder 28)
    Includes: memo from the Executive Office of President to the agency heads, other correspondence
  - Carroll Bill (S.1734), 1961 (Box 4, Folder 29-31)
  - Cases - Allis-Chalmers Manufacturing Company, Russell Scofield, American Baker and Confectionary Workers Local (Fine Cases). (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
    Includes: case decisions (Supreme Court and Circuit Court of Appeals), handwritten notes, legal memos
  - Cases - Darlington Mills, 1956-1969 (Box 5, Folder 3-5)
    Includes: case decisions, historical profile (1956-1969), news articles, memoranda
  - Cases - Gissell, Linden Lumber, Wilder (Card Cases) (Box 5, Folder 6-9)
    Includes: related cases and notes, data on 'card cases'
  - Cases - Gissell and thoughts on cards (pre-Gissell)., 1968 (Box 5, Folder 10-11)
    Includes: Law Review articles, brief for the Food Store Employees Union, Local 347, Amalgamated Meat Cutters and Butcher Workmen of North America, AFL-CIO of Supreme Court Case - NLRB v. Gissell Packing Co, Inc., October 1968
  - Cases - Gissell, Carborundum (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Includes: Supreme Court decision, Congressional Record.
  - Cases - Excelsior (Access Lists) (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Includes: Press release, text of cases
  - Cases - Comments on various cases (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Includes: news articles, correspondence, newsletters and case summaries
  - Cases - Miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 15-16)
    Includes: cases reviewed by the Supreme Court, re: craft severance, picketing work load, 8(b) violations, delays, reply from Ogden Fields on behalf of the NLRB to Senator Jenning Randolph re: constituent concern over case delays
  - Chamber of Commerce (Box 5, Folder 17-20)
    Includes: news articles, magazine articles, speeches and remarks at various conferences, NLRB Reform Kit, memos, correspondence.
  - Changes in the National Labor Relations Board (NLRB); (appointment of Edward Miller, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 21-23)
    Includes: Miller, Edward. "The Alice-in-Wonderland World of Public Employees." Chicago Bar Record (February 1969): 223-229., Miller, Edward. "How to Create Business for Labor Lawyers." The Business Lawyer (January 1970): 407-417., news articles, correspondence, transcript from press conference with George P. Schultz, Secretary of Labor, and Edward Miller, Chairman-Designate of the NLRB
  - Comments re: The National Labor Relations Board, 1963-1970 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
    Includes: news clippings, speeches, Congressional Record
  - Construction Industry - Multi-employer Certification (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Includes: Guy Farmer correspondence
  - Craft Severance (Box 6, Folder 4-6)
    Includes: papers from law reviews, correspondence, press releases, cases, special board agendas, handwritten notes, memoranda concerning particular cases
  - Delegation of Representation Cases to Regional Board (Box 6, Folder 7-8)
    Includes: amendments to rules and regulations and statements of procedures, memoranda, Federal Register
  - Election Notices and Pamphlets - New, 1966-1967 (Box 6, Folder 9-12)
    Includes: correspondence, posters, actual pamphlets and notices; also general notices about NLRB functions and election statistics
  - Employer Free Speech (Box 6, Folder 13-21)
    Includes: various cases before the NLRB and Circuit Courts, publications, pamphlets
  - Employer Resistance to Labor and the NLRB: pre 1968 (Box 6, Folder 22-28)
    Includes: news articles, magazine articles, speeches and remarks at various conferences, radio broadcasts
  - Employer Resistance to Labor and the NLRB: post 1969 (Box 6, Folder 29-31)
    Includes: news articles, magazine articles, employer postings from pre-election campaign period
  - Ervin subcommittee on separation of powers, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 1-17)
    Includes: 1964. Supplemental Memorandum of the National Labor Relations Board to the Subcommittee on the Separation of Powers, August, requests for information from Laurence Baskir, Frank McCulloch, and Arnold Ordman to Tim Bornstein and Bernard Cushman, materials from the Legislative Reference Service of the Library of Congress, statements of Frank McCulloch, Arnold Ordman Harry Wellington, Senator Paul Fannin, and Senator Robert Griffin before the Subcommittee, list of potential witnesses, US Chamber of Commerce Statement on HR 11725, newspaper articles, Congressional Record.
  - Ervin subcommittee on separation of powers - drafts of response to Ervin Subcommittee Report, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 18-19)
    Includes: United States. Cong. Senate. Congressional Oversight of Administrative Agencies (National Labor Relations Board). By Subcommittee on Separation of Powers. 91st Cong., 1st session. Committee Print. Washington: GPO 1970., McCulloch's comments, McCulloch and Arnold Ordman joint statement, press releases
  - Ervin Subcommittee on Separation of Powers - Materials for McCulloch's statement. (Box 7, Folder 20-23)
    Includes: prepared opening statement of Senator Ervin (Chairman of Subcommittee on Separation of Powers), Congressional Record, memoranda, McCulloch's handwritten notes, correspondence between Senator Ervin and the Office of the President, draft of The Roles of the National Labor Relations Board and its Relationship to Congress (author not named).
  - Ervin Subcommittee on Separation of Powers - pre-hearing letters (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Ervin Subcommittee on Separation of Powers - Procedural Issues Raised by the National labor Relations Board (NLRB), 1968 (Box 7, Folder 25-28)
    Re: unauthorized changes to McCulloch's testimony, failure to include supplemental memorandum submitted by McCulloch in the printed version of the testimony. Includes: transcripts of McCulloch's testimony before the Subcommittee on Separation of Powers, May 10, 1968, detailed account of all changes made, correspondence, memoranda.
  - Ervin-Burdick Drafts of Reports on NLRB (Box 7, Folder 29-32)
    Includes: confidential drafts of separate and dissenting views of Hon. Sam Ervin and Hon. Quentin Burdick (members of Subcommittee on the Separation of Power), Tim Bornstein notes, correspondence
  - Binder (no folder): Ervin Hearings - Tim Bornstein's editing and supporting data (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Examination of the Labor Movement in the 1970s, 1972-1973 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
    Includes: Sheed, William. "What Ever Happened to the Labor Movement." Atlantic Monthly. July 1973: 42-69., Daily Labor News - Special Edition (1972)
  - Fiberboard Case - Fiberboard Paper Products vs. National Labor Relations Board et al., 1964 (Box 8, Folder 3-11)
    Includes: text of cases, statistics on National Labor Relations Board (NLRB) cases, handwritten notes, memoranda, report send other information about subcontracting, reports on applications of the decision, case profiles, similar cases.
  - Fiberboard case - Section 8(a)(5) items (Box 8, Folder 12)
    Re: Olin Industries, Westinghouse
  - Foreign Flag Shippings (Box 8, Folder 13-16)
    Includes: correspondence with the Department of Labor, reports and memoranda, news clippings and magazine articles. Re: NLRB jurisdiction over foreign flag ships, Robinson-Patman Act, etc.
  - General Counsel's Area Conference Reports, 1965-1968 (Box 8, Folder 17-18)
    Includes: letter to Robert H. Michel, House of Representatives, in response to an inquiry, reports of Committee Chairmen (1965), reports of Workshop Chairmen (1968) memoranda
  - General Electric. (Box 8, Folder 19-24)
    Includes: court cases, news articles, journal articles, pamphlets. Re: Free Speech, Boulwarism, GE relations with International union of Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers (IUE)
  - General Electric - Coordinated Bargaining, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 25-29)
    includes: Jennings, Paul. "Coordinated Bargaining: The IUE Experience." Seminar on Union Government in Transition. University of Chicago, Chicago. 16-18 Nov. 1967, reports, statements, press releases, cases
  - German Co-Determination, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    includes: information gathered by Harry Brickman after Mr. O'Connell likened the NLRB Fibreboard doctrine to the German system of "co-determination" in a testimony before Congress (May 1968)
  - Government Employee Relations (Box 8, Folder 31)
    Includes: notes and proposals of the Employee-Management Cooperation Committee, proposal to establish a Federal Labor Relations Panel
  - Has Labor Law Failed? - mid 1980s, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 32-34)
    Includes: statements from hearing before House Labor Subcommittee on Labor-Management Relations examining the question "has labor law failed?" (June 1984), other reports and statements from hearings and conferences
  - House of Representatives hearings, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Includes: news articles, correspondence, handwritten notes, Building and Construction Trades Department, AFL-CIO. The House Passes a Common Situs Picketing Bill: After Twenty-Five Years. Building and Construction Trades Department AFL-CIO: Washington
  - House of Representatives Investigation of the National Labor Relations Act, 1965-1967 (Box 9, Folder 2-5)
    Includes: witness statements and other evidence
  - House of Representatives Investigation of NLRB, 1965-1967 (Box 9, Folder 6-8)
    Includes: statistics, election reports, testimonies Thompson Bill (HR 11725)
  - House of Representatives - Pucinski Hearings, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 9-13)
    Includes: United States. Cong. House. Administration of the Labor-Management Relations Act by the NLRB. 87th Cong. 1st sess. Committee Print. Washington: GPO, 1961. The Subcommittee's Work. Statement of Frank W. McCulloch before the Ad Hoc Subcommittee on NLRB of the Committee on Education and Labor, Washington, D.C. June., statements of Boyd Leedom and Philip Ray Rodgers, materials from Norton Come, memoranda, reports, handwritten notes.
  - Improved Service to the Public (Box 9, Folder 14)
    Includes: Correspondence between Civil Service Commission Chairmen, Hon. Robert E. Hampton and Hon. John W. Macy, Jr., and Associate General Counsel H. Stephan Gordon, information from the National labor Relations Board about a career as a field examiner
  - J.P. Stevens (Box 9, Folder 15-17)
    Includes: cases before the National Labor Relations Board (NLRB) and Circuit Courts of Appeals, news articles, background sheet on the company, correspondence, memoranda
  - Labor Court. (Box 9, Folder 18-19)
    Includes: legislative proposals, bills, Congressional Record, published reports
  - Labor in Crisis - 1980s (Box 9, Folder 20-23)
    Includes: Pamphlets, information about unions' new strategies, state reports, news articles
  - Labor Law Memos, 1961-1970 (Box 9, Folder 24-28)
    Re: Nursing homes, jurisdiction over universities (not-for-profit), agricultural laborers, subcontracting, contract-bars rules, picket lines, section 10(k) issues; Includes: announcement of the Department of Labor's "New and comprehensive series of studies of collective bargaining agreements."
  - Labor Law Reform, 1962-1972 (Box 9, Folder 29-35)
    Includes: Petro, Sylvester. "The National Labor Relations Board Must Go." Barron's Injudicious Agency. September 23 1968, journals, pamphlets, Congressional Record, speeches, news clippings
  - Labor Law Reform - Hill-Knowlton, Public Relations Campaign, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 1-5)
    Includes: Chamber of Commerce of the United States. The Need for Labor Law Reform. Washington, D.C. (no publication date given), Hill and Knowlton, Inc. Background Memorandum: The Need for Labor Law Reform. New York: Dec. 1967., other reports and memoranda by Hill and Knowlton, Inc. and the National Association of Manufacturers (NAM)
  - Labor Law Reform - Testimonies before Congress, 1962-1968 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    Includes: Congressional Record
  - Labor Law Reform Study, 1967-1969 (Box 10, Folder 7-9)